

Francesco Zaniol

Senior Frontend Engineer | Frontend Architect fzaniol@gmail.com | Linkedin

About

I am a Frontend Engineer with **15 years of industry experience**. I create fast, user-friendly, secure and accessible websites and apps, while delivering robust and efficient solutions.

Throughout my career I have contributed to **successful products and campaigns** for **leading international brands**, such as Bulgari, GEOX, Barilla, IKEA, Poste Italiane, Toyota, Whirpool, Loro Piana, SNAM, Henkel, Aquafil, FIAT, Telecom Italia, Illy, Bacardi, Fendi, Intesa Sanpaolo, OVS, Alessi, Sportsgirl, Telstra, Australia Post, Bupa, APT Australia, Movember, among others.

I work remotely from Italy and am open to B2B contracting opportunities, short or long term.

Top skills

Vue/Nuxt • React/Next • Typescript • Web Accessibility • Design System • Testing • Tailwind • Animations • Agile • Responsive Design • Git • API/GraphQL • Vite/Webpack • UX • Debugging • Performance • SEO • Cross-browser • Web Components • PHP • Laravel • Wordpress • DRY • Teamplayer

Work experience

Freelance

2024-Present • Italy (Full remote)

Role: Senior Frontend Engineer | Web Engineer

Vue/Nuxt, TypeScript, Animations, Wordpress, Browser Extensions

Clients: AKQA, local clients, startup

MAIZE | H-FARM Innovation | JAKALA

2018-2023 (5 years 6 months) • Italy (Full remote)

Role: Senior Frontend Engineer | Frontend Architect

Vue/Nuxt, React, TypeScript, Testing, Design Systems, Laravel, Animations, Agile

Clients: Italian Industry Leaders and Multinational Corporations

Brands in the fields of: Banking, Insurance, Luxury, Eyewear, Automotive, Telecoms, Clothing, Digital Learning, Aerospace, Defense and Security

IE Agency

2014-2017 (3 years) • Melbourne, Australia

Role: Lead Frontend Developer | Mentor

Team Lead & Mentor, Agile, Design System, Testing, React, PHP, Zend

Client: The Movember Foundation (movember.com) and Australian Industry Leaders Movember is one of the World's top 100 NGOs • Global Fundraising | 1.8 billion raised | 1.7 million

participants

AKQA | H-ART

2012-2013 (1 year 6 months) • Italy

Role: Frontend Developer

Animations, Landing Pages, Wordpress, Drupal

Clients: Italian Industry Leaders and Multinational Corporations

Brands in the fields of: Food & Drink Industry, Automotive, Banking, Insurance, Luxury, Telecoms, Clothing, Home Appliances

accessibletemplate.com

2012-2017 (5 years 2 months) • Worldwide | Online digital store

Role: Founder | Fullstack Engineer

Accessibility, Personal Business, Joomla Templates, PHP

Clients: Private & Government Websites

WCAG, European Accessibility Act, Section 508, Equality Act, Legge Stanca

AWDD Media

2010 (7 months) • Vancouver, Canada

Role: Frontend Developer

Drupal, PSD to HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, HTML5

Clients: Local Businesses

Freelance

2008-2011 (3 years 5 months) • Italy

Role: Web Developer

Joomla Websites

Clients: Local Businesses

Education

Ca' Foscari University, Venice

2004 - 2008 (3 years 6 months)

Degree, Information Technology

Grade: 107/110

ITIS Max Plank

1999 - 2004 (5 years)

High school diploma, Information Technology

Grade: 100/100